♪I lament on the cruel and untimely love♪
أنا أتحسر على الحب القاسي والغير أوانه ♪
♪Yet I come to realise it's a daydream when the bubbles burst♪
♪ ومع ذلك أدركت أنه حلم يقظة عندما تنفجر الفقاعات ♪
♪A city of spring flowers♪
♪ مدينة زهور الربيع ♪
♪Sinks into the indifferent autumnal frost♪
♪ يغرق في الصقيع الخريفي غير المبال
♪A snowflake falls into the river♪
♪ تسقط ندفة ثلجية في النهر ♪
♪The biting cold stalks over♪
♪ البرد القارص ينبع
♪All assumptions are nothing♪
كل الافتراضات لا شيء
♪But a disguised makeup♪
♪ لكن مكياج مقنع
♪I bid farewell♪
أودع
♪To the passionate gaze behind the mask♪
♪ للنظرة العاطفية خلف القناع ♪
♪Love and hate are the most unforgettable feelings♪
الحب والكراهية من أكثر المشاعر التي لا تنسى
♪Overwhelmed by my longings♪
غارقة في شوقي ♪
♪I tear off those old scores♪
♪ مزقت تلك الدرجات القديمة ♪
♪I bid farewell♪
أودع
♪To the irretrievable past♪
إلى الماضي الذي لا يمكن استرجاعه ♪
=Little Mad Doctor=
= الطبيب المجنون الصغير =
=Episode 17=
= الحلقة 17 =
What if
ماذا إذا
I'm a lowly person?
أنا شخص متواضع؟
Lowly...person?
متواضع ... شخص؟
Greetings, Second Prince.
تحياتي ، الأمير الثاني.
Please forgive me.
رجائاً أعطني.
What a shame.
يا للعار.
The dessert fell
سقطت الحلوى
before I get a bite.
قبل أن أحصل على لدغة.
Please forgive me.
رجائاً أعطني.
Please grant me a chance.
من فضلك امنحني فرصة.
I can prepare a new dessert for you.
يمكنني تحضير حلوى جديدة لك.
What's your name?
ما اسمك؟
I'm Jin'er.
أنا جينير.
Jin'er.
جينير.
Well.
حسنًا.
I shall taste the dessert
سوف أتذوق الحلوى
you make right now.
تقوم به الآن.
Yes.
نعم.
It tastes
مذاقه
pretty good.
جيد جدا.
But
لكن
something lacks.
شيء ينقصه.
Something lacks?
شيء ما ينقصه؟
Everything
كل شئ
possesses a feeling.
يمتلك شعوراً.
If you treat her well,
إذا عاملتها بشكل جيد ،
she will repay the kindness you extend.
سوف تسدد اللطف الذي تقدمه.
Just like what I did to you.
تماما مثل ما فعلته لك.
I granted you grace and you will remember it.
لقد منحتك نعمة وسوف تتذكرها.
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
Please forgive me.
رجائاً أعطني.
I'm incapable.
أنا عاجز.
Why are you shivering?
لماذا ترتجف
I savored the lotus cake,
لقد استمتعت بكعكة اللوتس ،
but there's something I have yet to taste it.
ولكن هناك شيء لم أتذوقه بعد.
Do consider what I have said.
لا تنظر في ما قلته.
Deliver me the lotus cake
سلمني كعكة اللوتس
that carries some feelings a few days later.
يحمل بعض المشاعر بعد أيام قليلة.
Jin'er.
جينير.
What took you so long?
ما الذي أخرك؟
Ah.
آه.
I just went back to the palace.
لقد عدت للتو إلى القصر.
It's been a long while
لقد مر وقت طويل
and I forgot where I placed the clothes.
ونسيت المكان الذي وضعت فيه الملابس.
Jin'er.
جينير.
Did you buy a new hairpin?
هل اشتريت دبوس شعر جديد؟
Ah?
آه؟
Oh.
أوه.
I passed by a stall just now.
مررت بكشك للتو.
I bought it
اشتريته
because it looks dainty.
لأنها تبدو لذيذة.
Show it to me.
أرني إياه.
It must be pretty
يجب أن تكون جميلة
if I wear it.
إذا ارتديته.
I need to head back
أنا بحاجة للعودة
to my room now.
إلى غرفتي الآن.
Hmph!
همف!
How petty.
كيف تافه.
It's a mere hairpin.
إنه مجرد دبوس شعر.
Jin'er.
جينير.
Are you going out again?
هل ستخرج مرة أخرى؟
Yes.
نعم.
I went to purchase something for Her Highness.
ذهبت لشراء شيء لسمو الشيخة.
I see.
أرى.
Jin'er has been going out a dozen times recently.
كان Jin'er يخرج عشرات المرات مؤخرًا.
Have you done
هل انتهيت
what I entrusted you?
ما ائتمنتك؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Jin'er.
جينير.
You come at the right time.
أتيت في الوقت المناسب.
Come on.
تعال.
Let's start the mobile clinic.
لنبدأ العيادة المتنقلة.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Today is the first day of the month, there's a lantern festival.
اليوم هو أول أيام الشهر ، وهناك مهرجان فوانيس.
Let's go there.
فلنذهب إلى هناك.
Lantern festival?
مهرجان الفوانيس؟
It's really fun
إنه حقا ممتع
and much delicious food there.
والكثير من الطعام اللذيذ هناك.
Really?
حقًا؟
Yes.
نعم.
That's right.
صحيح.
I guess
اعتقد
not many people would come
لن يأتي الكثير من الناس
to the clinic today.
إلى العيادة اليوم.
You have a point.
لديك نقطة.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Let's go to the lantern festival.
دعنا نذهب إلى مهرجان الفوانيس.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
I will invite His Highness.
سأدعو سموه.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
His Highness
صاحب السمو
doesn't like crowdy events.
لا يحب الأحداث المزدحمة.
Also,
أيضًا،
it's ill-advised
إنه غير حكيم
if someone recognizes His Highness there.
إذا اعترف أحدهم بسمو هناك.
You're right.
أنت على حق.
Well, let's go.
حسنًا ، دعنا نذهب.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
There are lantern riddles ahead.
هناك ألغاز فانوس أمامنا.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
I'm really good at this.
أنا جيد حقًا في هذا.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
How's she?
كيف حالها؟
No worries.
لا شكر على واجب.
I suppose she's fine.
أعتقد أنها بخير.
You suppose?
افترض؟
I want a confirmed answer.
اريد اجابة مؤكدة.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Please remain composed.
من فضلك حافظ على رباطة جأشك.
She will be fine
ستكون بخير
since the imperial physician said so.
منذ أن قال الطبيب الإمبراطوري ذلك.
But she hasn't woken up yet.
لكنها لم تستيقظ بعد.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
If Princess Jinghong were to wake up now,
إذا استيقظت الأميرة جينغ هونغ الآن ،
she will definitely seek Lord War.
ستسعى بالتأكيد إلى حرب اللورد.
And you will lose your chance.
وستفقد فرصتك.
Also,
أيضًا،
Lord War
حرب اللورد
will come to seek her too.
سيأتي للبحث عنها أيضًا.
She's going to marry him soon.
سوف تتزوجه قريباً.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
You...
أنت...
Can you figure out something
هل يمكنك اكتشاف شيء ما
to halt her marriage?
لوقف زواجها؟
There's nothing much I can do.
لا يوجد الكثير يمكنني القيام به.
Both of them have one final step left
كلاهما لديه خطوة أخيرة متبقية
to become a truly married couple.
أن يصبحا زوجًا حقيقيًا.
Final step left?
هل تركت الخطوة الأخيرة؟
What if
ماذا إذا
I take the final step?
أتخذ الخطوة الأخيرة؟
Can I bring everything back to where it started?
هل يمكنني إعادة كل شيء إلى حيث بدأ؟
I...
أنا...
I didn't do anything.
لم أفعل أي شيء.
Why am I here?
لماذا انا هنا؟
My Lord.
ربي.
I've used ice and herbs
لقد استخدمت الثلج والأعشاب
to suppress
يقمع
the poison in you.
السم فيك.
But this is only a stopgap.
لكن هذه ليست سوى فجوة مؤقتة.
My Lord.
ربي.
Something bad has happened!
حدث شيء سيء!
Her Highness was carried away by Second Prince.
حملت سموها من قبل الأمير الثاني.
What?
ماذا؟
I will forget this happened
سوف انسى هذا حدث
since you saved me
منذ أن أنقذتني
today.
اليوم.
Are you leaving?
هل أنت ذاهب؟
You can't go.
لا يمكنك الذهاب.
You can't go to Uncle Thirteen.
لا يمكنك الذهاب إلى العم الثالث عشر.
Yu Heng.
يو هنغ.
We've not related anymore.
لم نعد نرتبط بعد الآن.
Please behave yourself.
يرجى تتصرف نفسك.
Don't go.
لا تذهب.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
♪I sigh at my life♪
♪ أنا أتنهد في حياتي ♪
♪There's nowhere to anchor on shore♪
♪ لا يوجد مكان للرسو على الشاطئ
♪Nothing to cherish in the world♪
لا شيء نعتز به في العالم
♪Except for you♪
ما عداك ♪
♪The past we've been through retains♪
♪ الماضي الذي مررنا به
♪Even though time wears thin♪
على الرغم من أن الوقت يضعف ♪
♪The thought of being together lifelong♪
فكرة البقاء معًا مدى الحياة
♪Exists beyond time♪
موجود خارج الزمن ♪
♪All joys and sorrows♪
♪ كل افراح و احزان ♪
♪Reflect in your gentle gaze♪
انعكس في نظراتك اللطيفة
♪I will spend my life waiting♪
♪ سأقضي حياتي في الانتظار ♪
♪For the chance to be forever by your side♪
للحصول على فرصة أن تكون بجانبك إلى الأبد
♪Hair turns grey in one winter night♪
♪ يتحول لون الشعر إلى اللون الرمادي في ليلة شتاء ♪
♪The appearance remains in spite of the thick frost♪
المظهر يبقى بالرغم من الصقيع الكثيف
♪Time slips by in that dream-like world♪
♪ الوقت يمر في هذا العالم الذي يشبه الحلم
♪Life is always full of splendor♪
♪ الحياة دائما مليئة بالروعة
♪We part when the flowers fall♪
♪ نفترق عندما تسقط الأزهار
♪Desolate chills blow away several autumns♪
♪ قشعريرة مقفرة تهب عدة خريفات ♪
♪Eternal love is all I seek♪
الحب الأبدي هو كل ما أسعى إليه
♪Though the sweet dream fades at last♪
رغم أن الحلم الجميل يتلاشى أخيرًا ♪
♪I sigh at my life♪
♪ أنا أتنهد في حياتي ♪
♪There's nowhere to anchor on shore♪
♪ لا يوجد مكان للرسو على الشاطئ
♪Nothing to cherish in the world♪
لا شيء نعتز به في العالم
♪Except for you♪
ما عداك ♪
♪The past we've been through retains♪
♪ الماضي الذي مررنا به
♪Even though time wears thin♪
على الرغم من أن الوقت يضعف ♪
♪The thought of being together lifelong♪
فكرة البقاء معًا مدى الحياة
♪Exists beyond time♪
موجود خارج الزمن ♪
♪All joys and sorrows♪
♪ كل افراح و احزان ♪
♪Reflect in your gentle gaze♪
انعكس في نظراتك اللطيفة
♪I will spend my life waiting♪
♪ سأقضي حياتي في الانتظار ♪
♪For the chance to be forever by your side♪
للحصول على فرصة أن تكون بجانبك إلى الأبد